<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Learner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-23T16:18:06+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://codeplan.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Avdesh Singh]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beware, another spider OSINT is coming to the web]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/06/22/beware/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-22T19:43:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/06/22/beware</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After startling revelations about the US&#8217; long-running Prism internet surveillance programme comes the news that Delhi Police is also readying a similar system to snoop on social networks and internet communications. It has already invited global IT giants to help set up a lab and train manpower for the project.</p>

<p>Named Osint ( Open Source Intelligent Solution), the system will be used to extract and analyze information available on the internet. Police sources say criminals and terrorists now mostly communicate online to avoid detection, so Osint will focus on gathering &lsquo;actionable intelligence&#8217;—ready information to deal with a situation—and &#8216;sentiment analysis&#8217;—psychological analysis of the communication to preempt a crime—by collecting and analysing data from online sources.</p>

<p>Osint will also help police profile suspects and index information about them. For sentiment analysis, it will tap into social media like Facebook, Twitter, public forums and blogs. Equally important will be its ability to sift relevant details from a heap of information, and render them usable. This will speed up investigations as police will be able to tally new information with their crime database. With context and object identification, the system will be able to discover related material online and identify people, places, organizations etc.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&ldquo;The internet can be a vital source of information for law enforcement agencies to identify criminals and criminal activities. It is probably the largest source of data today with valuable, real-time information coursing through it,&rdquo; said an officer, adding, &ldquo;This technology is increasingly being used in Europe and will alert us to the anti-social or criminal motives of a person or group&rdquo;.</p>

<p>The system will be able to extract data in any format— text, Office documents, PDFs, flat files, images, audio, video and even files accessible via protocols—from any website in the public domain. It will support encoding for languages like Arabic and Hebrew that are bidirectional.</p>

<p>&mdash;source: Times of India</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Mail Merging]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/06/01/learn-mail-merging/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-01T19:13:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/06/01/learn-mail-merging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A mail merge program helps you send personalized email messages to multiple contacts in one go. Each message has the same content but some parts of the message can be customized – like you can greet each recipient by their first name.</p>

<p>Who needs Mail Merge?
If you are organizing a party at your home, you can send personalized email invitations to all your friends with the help of mail merge. A person like Steve Jobs – see the following video – can use mail merge to effortlessly invite his inner circle for the launch of a new product.</p>

<p><img src="http://t3kd.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/gmail-google-docs-mail-merge-705x320.jpg"></p>

<p>Go to this link to learn compose the mail and merge: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;v=B6Ehz2i6eU4">http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;v=B6Ehz2i6eU4</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook going to be replaced by Diaspora]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/05/31/facebook-going-to-be-replaced-by-diaspora/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T15:55:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/05/31/facebook-going-to-be-replaced-by-diaspora</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Diaspora (stylized DIASPORA*) is a free personal web server that implements a distributed social networking service. Installations of the software form nodes (termed &ldquo;pods&rdquo;) which make up the distributed Diaspora social network.
The project was founded by Dan Grippi, Maxwell Salzberg, Raphael Sofaer and Ilya Zhitomirskiy, students at New York University&rsquo;s Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences. The group received donations in excess of $200,000 via Kickstarter. A consumer alpha version was released on November 23, 2010.</p>

<p>Diaspora is intended to address privacy concerns related to centralized social networks by allowing users set up their own server (or &ldquo;pod&rdquo;) to host content; pods can then interact to share status updates, photographs, and other social data.It allows its users to host their data with a traditional web host, a cloud-based host, an ISP, or a friend. The framework, which is being built on Ruby on Rails, is free software and can be experimented with by external developers.
A key part of the Diaspora software design concept is that it should act as a &ldquo;social aggregator&rdquo;, allowing posts to be easily imported from Facebook, Tumblr and Twitter. As Village Voice writer Nick Pinto explained, &ldquo;the idea is that this lowers the barriers to joining the network, and as more of your friends join, you no longer need to bounce communications through Facebook. Instead, you can communicate directly, securely, and without running exchanges past the prying eyes of Zuckerberg and his business associates.&rdquo;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://notizblog.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/diaspora.jpg"></p>

<p>The powerfull features of Diaspora:</p>

<p>The Diaspora software allows user posts to be designated as &ldquo;public&rdquo; or &ldquo;limited&rdquo;. In the latter case, posts may only be read by approved groups (or combinations of groups) set up by the user, termed aspects. Several default aspects exist such as friends, family, or work and custom ones may be added. It is possible to follow another user&rsquo;s post without the mutual friending required by other social networks.A user&rsquo;s news stream may be filtered by aspect.
The developers consider the distributed nature of the network crucial to its design and success:</p>

<p>&ldquo;Diaspora’s distributed design is a huge part of it. Like the Internet itself, Diaspora<em> isn’t housed in any one place, and it’s not controlled by any one entity (including us). We’ve created software that lets you set up and run your own social network on your own “pod” (or server) and connect your network to the larger Diaspora</em> ecosystem. You can have a pod all to yourself, or one for just you and your friends, or your family, giving you complete ownership and control over your personal social information (including your identity, your posts, and your photos) and how it’s all stored and shared. Or you can simply request an invite at joindiaspora.com, or sign up at one of more than 20 open pods.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Diaspora users retain ownership of their data and do not assign ownership rights. The software is specifically designed to allow users to download all their images and text that has been uploaded at any time.
In September 2011, although the network and its software was still in alpha, Terry Hancock of Free Software Magazine described it as &ldquo;already quite usable for some purposes&rdquo;. While it supported text, photographs, and links, it still lacked some features, including link preview, the ability to upload or embed videos (although videos could be linked to on other services) and chat. Animated GIFs were supported, however.
Video embedding from YouTube and Vimeo was added in early 2012.</p>

<p>The Diaspora Team:
<img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b9/Diaspora_team.jpg"></p>

<p>Watch video to see the power of Diaspora:</p>

<p><video width='500' height='500' preload='none' controls poster=''><source src='http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&v=_4mMSxWEnjU' ></video></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
