<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Learner's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-31T16:35:55+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://codeplan.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Avdesh Singh]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook going to replaced by Diaspora]]></title>
    <link href="http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/05/31/facebook-going-to-replaced-by-diaspora/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T15:55:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://codeplan.github.io/blog/2013/05/31/facebook-going-to-replaced-by-diaspora</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Diaspora (stylized DIASPORA*) is a free personal web server that implements a distributed social networking service. Installations of the software form nodes (termed &ldquo;pods&rdquo;) which make up the distributed Diaspora social network.
The project was founded by Dan Grippi, Maxwell Salzberg, Raphael Sofaer and Ilya Zhitomirskiy, students at New York University&rsquo;s Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences. The group received donations in excess of $200,000 via Kickstarter. A consumer alpha version was released on November 23, 2010.</p>

<p>Diaspora is intended to address privacy concerns related to centralized social networks by allowing users set up their own server (or &ldquo;pod&rdquo;) to host content; pods can then interact to share status updates, photographs, and other social data.[6] It allows its users to host their data with a traditional web host, a cloud-based host, an ISP, or a friend. The framework, which is being built on Ruby on Rails, is free software and can be experimented with by external developers.
A key part of the Diaspora software design concept is that it should act as a &ldquo;social aggregator&rdquo;, allowing posts to be easily imported from Facebook, Tumblr and Twitter. As Village Voice writer Nick Pinto explained, &ldquo;the idea is that this lowers the barriers to joining the network, and as more of your friends join, you no longer need to bounce communications through Facebook. Instead, you can communicate directly, securely, and without running exchanges past the prying eyes of Zuckerberg and his business associates.&rdquo;</p>

<p><img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/58/Diaspora_latest.png" width="1000" height="1000"></p>

<p>Watch video:</p>

<p><video width='10' height='10' preload='none' controls poster='http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&v=_4mMSxWEnjU.png'><source src='http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&v=_4mMSxWEnjU' ></video></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
